2 Years in Dynamics AX + 10 Years in .NET

Ajay Solanki

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Total 12 years of experience in IT Industry this includes 10 years' experience on .Net technologies and 2 years on Microsoft Dynamics AX2012.

Curious, Quick Learner & Team player

Total Years of Experience : 12 Years
Total Years of Dynamics AX Experience : 2 Years
Total Years of .Net Experience : 10 Years

Current Industry : .NET Freelander, nopCommerce customizations & plugins

Current Technical Area : Dynamics AX, .NET, nopCommerce

Experience Summary

.Net Experience

- Started career with web technologies using Asp.net
- Web services (API) development for mobile applications.
- Windows services to perform backend jobs
- Worked on nopCommerce an Open source .net e-commerce
- nopCommerce payment gateway plugin development
- Worked on different customizations and plugin development for nopCommerce

Dynamics AX Experience

- X++ code, development and debugging in MorphX IDE
- Integration with Dynamics AX using .Net Business Connector
- Developing and customizing existing forms
- Generating of SSRS reports using RDP and Query Based.
- Using AIF Services
- Data Import/Export Frame work import/export data to and from AX

Ajay Solanki
Developer .Net & Dynamics AX
Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

IT Experience

July 2023 – November 2023	BrainerHub SolutionsNET Tech Lead Roles and Responsibilities:
June 2016 – July 2023	Freelance developer working independently Roles and Responsibilities: Client communication – requirement gathering Find best possible solution to problem Development & Testing Support
Sep 2014 – June 2016	INDUSA Infotech Services Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India http://www.indusa.com/ Designation: Software Engineer in Dynamics Ax Team Roles and Responsibilities: Development & Testing Call/Meeting with functional team members/client for requirement and work discussion Deployment

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

Aug 2011 – Aug 2014	WEBLINEINDIA, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India http://www.weblineindia.com/		
	Designation : .Net Developer		
	Roles and Responsibilities:		
	 Coding & Testing Client Communication/Reporting Requirement gathering / Analysis Task assignment Training team members 		

Education

Completed	Institution	Degree / Qualification
2011	VGEC, Chandkheda, Ahmedabad	B.E. Computer
2008	K.D. Polytechnic, Patan	Diploma in Computer Engineering
2004	L. S. Highschool, Siddhpur	12 th Science Stream

Technical Skills

ERP Packages : Microsoft Dynamics Ax2012

Programming Languages : X++, C#

eCommerce : nopCommerce

Database : SQL Server 2008, SQL Server 2012, MySQL, SQLite Operating System : Windows Server 2008/2012, Windows 7, Windows 8

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

Project Details

Dynamics AX Projects

WCF Web Service Development & Windows Service Development for Mobile Application – Integration with Dynamics Ax 2009

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, WCF, Dynamics Ax 2009, SQL Server 2012, .Net Business Connector for Dynamics Ax

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

Client is developing mobile application for their internal Service Management System which is integrated with AX 2009, Developed web services for getting data from their system to mobile in JSON format & getting master data updated from AX 2009 to intermediate database periodically using Windows Service, Used .net business connector to get data from AX 2009

Web Service using .net business connector using Dynamics Ax 2012

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, WCF, Dynamics Ax 2012, SQL Server 2012, .Net Business Connector for Dynamics Ax

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

WCF Web services to list and create entities to and from AX 2012.

Creating and listing customers, sales orders, leads, opportunities from mobiles application using WCF service, WCF service is using .net business connector to get and created entities in AX 2012.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

Import sales order from other ERP to AX using Excel File, SSRS Report

Technologies Used In Project:

Dynamics AX 2012, X++

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

Client is using another ERP for Sales, they want to import sales orders from another ERP to AX 2012. They have exported excel from another ERP as input and we need to create entries in general journal from that excel in AX.

Created interface to upload excel, read excel parse data, code to create general journal entries, validate entries

Created error handling page which display all errors occurred during processing and also have function to retry by modifying data used to creating record

Provided configuration for saving setting and configuration for importing excel

Also worked for developing one SSRS report the same project

Data Migration Framework (DMF)/Data Import Export Framework (DIXF)

Technologies Used In Project:

Dynamics AX 2012, X++

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

Created DMF entities to import data for custom entities of custom module. Customized standard DMF module to support composite entities, Export xml with data, Also updated error handing and prepared form to display errors occurred during import process. Also added feature to edit value in error log and have retry facility.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

.Net Projects

NOPCOMMERCE - Whole Sale DVDs online store

Technologies Used in Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE 4.0, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Client Communication, Development, Testing & Deployment

About Project:

This was a big project with multiple solutions developed & integration

- 1) Setup DVD online site on nopCommerce 4.0
- 2) Automated solution for placing vendor purchase orders based on new orders received on store
- 3) Inventory management system which manage
 - -Vendor purchase order listing,
 - -Receiving items to warehouses,
 - -Managing Stocks
 - -Automatic Allocation to new orders
 - -Managing Picklist
 - -Various Reports with export
- 4) Scheduled Tasks to perform different job to make the process fully automated Sending Email Reminders

Uploading files to FTP for order processing

Managing log files

NOPCOMMERCE - Weekly meal plan delivery site

Technologies Used in Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE 3.80, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Client Communication, Development, Testing & Deployment

About Project:

Managing a weekly meal plan delivery project which is developed using nopCommerce 3.80. Working on improvement, adding new features and technical support.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

Various Web APIs Integration

Technologies Used in Projects:

C#, MVC

My Role in Project:

Developer

About:

Worked on different API integration project, Below are some APIs I've worked with.

Amazon MWS (Market Place Web Service)

Getting list of product and updating/setting price based on competitor price for the same items.

DHL Label Generating

DHL labels & manifest generating and printing for shipments.

FedEx Label API

FedEx label generating using API.

Spotify API

Pre-Save upcoming album on user's playlist.

This includes getting album details, managing user's playlist and add/update playlist using API.

Football API:

Getting team, events, venue data. Getting match results and save them in database for our custom prediction game.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

NOPCOMMERCE -Plugin for customized product and pricing for AHU(Air Handing Units)

Technologies Used in Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE 4.20, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Client Communication, Development

About Project:

This was also an interesting one, Here they want to have a custom product (Damper) for an AHU manufacturing company.

For that in plugin we've developed custom page where user can select various input parameters and based on that we need to prepare a custom damper and it's price is based on business logic used by one another software they were using for actual design.

Based on output we also need to manipulate and add some details and on images and prepare image for product based on different output parameters like number of dampers, spindles and type.

It was different one than simple CRUD project. Finally we were able to get the desired output and custom product generated and added to system is it is not available with the same parameters. And also price set based on output parameters and user get is desired custom product based on requirements.

NOPCOMMERCE - Payment Plugin Development

http://www.e-xact.com/

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE SOURCE CODE, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

Payment plugin development for e-Xact payment gateway for nopCommerce version 3.20 & version 1.80

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

NOPCOMMERCE - Adding new functions & Customizations

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE SOURCE CODE, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

Added new feature to select ship to options which will be associated with customer orders, filter shopping cart item based on selected ship to option, custom prices based on price matrix that depends on logged in customer and other business logics, customizing checkout process removed few steps and customized checkout flow.

NOPCOMMERCE - ERP SYSTEM INTEGRATION

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, MVC, NOPCOMMERCE SOURCE CODE, SQL SERVER, ERP'S COM+ COMPONENTS API

My Role in Project:

Project Lead, Client Interface, Developer

About Project:

This is one the biggest project of my career so far. I've worked for more than 1.5 year in this project. We had requirement of integrating NopCommerce with ERP system & automatic moving entities back & forth from NopCommerce to ERP and vice versa.

We used ERP's API's and developed web service in NopCommerce to move data to and from both systems.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

Web service development for mobile app project

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, ASP.NET, SQL SERVER

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

It was an application to send documents using iOS devices to service provider (our client), They get documents and print them and send to destination address.

My role in this project is to develop logic to calculate page count word document and PDF and calculate total charge based on number of pages there in document.

And develop web service to send documents in web service, and other web service for registration, login etc.

Slideshow video generation using third party api

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, My SQL, BytesScout Image to Video SDK

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

This was very interesting & my very first project. In this we need to create custom video from images and sound files uploaded from iPhone App, We need to get all sound files and images, then merge & mix all sound files into one and prepare video presentation using a third party sdk.

Once video is created we need to convert it into mp4/m4v for iPhone and provide link to download videos to user.

Developer .Net & Dynamics AX Contact: +91 9998922987

Email Id: ajay.solanki86@outlook.com

COOKIE Manager Windows Application

Technologies Used In Project:

C#, SQLITE Database

My Role in Project:

Developer

About Project:

This is small software to manage unwanted cookies on computer. Once we install this software in machine it will scan browsers and prepare list of sites which were visited from history and show a list of sites.

We can manage safe sites which we want to keep in secure sites list out software want remove cookies from these sites. And is don't keep site in safe list then it will remove cookies of those sites computer.

Once we start browser and surf for some sites and when we close the browser it will prompt the site we surfed in that session and ask us to add sites in safe list and it will remove cookies for sites if we don't add them in safe sites list

It also manage safe sites rating from community. We are passing statistics how many members have added some sites in safe listing and based on it is providing sites with ratings.

Personal Details

Name : Ajay Hareshbhai Solanki

• Gender : Male

• D.O.B : 20th October 1986

• Nationality : Indian

• Languages : Gujarati, Hindi, English

Hobbies : Playing Harmonica, Listening Music, Travelling